我发现他挺忧伤
I find he's sad.
什么  你在说什么
What?  What are you talking about?
伍尔希先生  看上去挺寂寞
Mr.Woolsey. it seems he's lonely
-有么  -他从来不参加城里的社交活动
He does? Never take parts in any of the city's social activities.
拜托
Oh, please. I mean...
他总是一个人吃饭
He always eats alone,
不是在自己办公室就是在他住处
Either in his office or in his quarters.
他可能有活要干
Maybe he has work to do, you know?
我们中有些人就是大忙人
Some of us are busy people.
有时候我夜里经过他住处
Sometimes, when I walk by his quarters at night,
听见他在哭
I hear him crying.
什么  真的
What? really?
假的
No.
伍尔希先生
Mr. woolsey!
要不要一起吃
Would you care to join us?
多谢了
Well, thank you,
但我今天得在房里
But I'll be taking breakfast
吃早餐
In my quarters today.
我还剩一点业绩评估
I still have some final preparations
没弄完
For my impending performance evaluation.
我有点担心
I'm a little apprehensive.
别那么担心
You shouldn't be.
作为我们的指挥官你做很出色
You've done a wonderful job as our new commander.
希望勘察顾问组也这么想
Well, let's hope the i.o.a. agrees.
看到了吧
There you go.
他就喜欢一个人待着
He prefers to be on his own.
话说回来  谢帕德去哪儿了
Speaking of which, where's sheppard?
今早他带了几个太空生物学家去陆地了
He flew some astrobiologists to the mainland this morning.
并自愿
And volunteered
陪他们在那儿过夜
To stay with them overnight.
真的
He did?
为什么
Why would he do that?
这个星球上的太阳是G级行星
This planet's sun is a class G star.
该条件连同
That fact, coupled with
与地球类似的大气组成成分
Its earth-like atmospheric composition,
为绿色光合有机物的生长
Results in the predominance
提供了有利环境
Of green photosynthetic organisms.
当然啦  叶绿素
Chlorophyll, of course,
吸收了大部分
Mostly absorbs
蓝光和红光的波长
The sun's blue and red wavelengths,
反射出绿色
Reflecting green ones.
你可能在想"等等"
"but hang on a minute," you're probably thinking.
"真奇怪"
"that's strange.
"为什么叶绿素不吸收绿光"
Why doesn't chlorophyll absorb green light?"
是啊  很奇怪  那为什么呢
Oh, yeah. weird. well, why doesn't it?
答案可不在
The answer lies not so much in the--
上帝啊
Oh, my god!
在这儿等着
Wait here.
怎么了
What happened?
瞧瞧这个
Look at this. huh?
这植物多像毛柄秋海棠
It's a plant not unlike the begonia eiromischa!
天哪
Oh, god.
罗恩提醒过我的
Lorne warned me about this.
你不懂
You don't understand.
这种有毛高茎秋海棠属植物
The woolly-stalked begonia
只有在2007年的地球上才有
Went officially extinct back on earth in 2007
我们就站在这儿
And yet here we are,
站在这株极其相似的植物旁边
Standing over a species that's shockingly similar--
我得回飞船了
I'm going to go back to the jumper
准备过夜
And set up for the night.
在这种环境中仍然生机勃勃
...and it's thriving in a climate that is...
要来么
Want to join me?
这真是罕见
It's a very unusual find.
行
Right.
尽情玩  别客气
Well, knock yourself out.
真是不虚此行啊
That's what we're here for.
慢慢来
Take your time.
我们整晚都在
We're here all night.
要帮忙么
Can I give you a hand with that?
其实  如果你不介意
Actually, if you wouldn't mind...
你好
Hello.
Hi.
你去哪儿
Where are you headed?
回我住处
Back to my quarters.
东南部码头
Um, the southeast pier.
第19层
Level 19.
住在顶楼
Ooh, penthouse suite.
不错
Nice.
我们认识么
Have we met?
不  我是瓦纳萨·康拉德
Not yet. I'm vanessa conrad.
瓦内萨·康拉德博士
Dr. vanessa conrad.
理查德·伍尔希
Richard woolsey.
我最近刚到阿波罗号
I just recently arrived on the apollo.
欢迎来到亚特兰蒂斯
Oh, welcome to atlantis.
谢谢
Thank you.
这儿很漂亮  也很大
It's beautiful. and huge.
搞清楚路恐怕得要好几个星期
It's probably going to be weeks before I know my way around.
我想指导部的人会帮你
Well, I'm sure the gang at orientation
慢慢习惯的
Will help you settle in.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
耽误你了
I'm keeping you.
东南码头  第19层
Southeast pier, level 19.
没有  一点没有
No, no. not at all.
我一直在
I have all the time in the--
就是这儿吧
This is you, I believe.
是啊
Oh. right.
那
Well.
很高兴见到你  博士
Nice to meet you, doctor.
瓦纳萨
Vanessa.
你可以叫我瓦纳萨
You can call me vanessa.
很好
Very well.
很高兴见到你  瓦纳萨
Nice to meet you, vanessa.
谢谢  伍尔希博士
Thank you, mr. woolsey.
其实  你可以叫我
Actually, you can call me--
妈的
Dick.
靠
Crap.
令你大惊小怪的外世宴会呢
What happened to your off-world foofaraw?
我还以为你是
I thought you were the guest of honor
外交晚宴上的贵宾呢
At some big diplomatic dinner on m2j?
本来是的
Yeah, I was,
但宴会提前结束了
But the festivities ended early
多诺万中尉队里的三个人
When three members of lieutenant donovan's team
对我们在宴会上供应的某种食物
Suffered a severe allergic reaction
产生了严重的过敏反应
To something we were served at the grand banquet.
我想可能是
I think it might have been
那种长紫斑的绿浆果有问题
Those little green berries with the purple specks on them,
我吃过后舌头就有点麻
Because my tongue did feel a little bit numb afterwards--
仅供参考
Yeah, fyi,
该对话结束于六秒前
This conversation ended six seconds ago.
好吧  总之
Yeah, anyway,
回来的路上  我有个主意
On the way back, I had an idea.
打个小盹就忘了
Have a little lie-down. it'll pass.
不是
No, uh...
你得听我说
You should hear me out.
我觉得应该扫描下
I think we should run a scan
海底
Of the ocean floor.
我发现城周围的水温
I've been noticing anomalous temperature variations
有异常的变化
In the waters surrounding the city.
需要进一步调查
I think it bears Further investigation.
不用啊
Not really.
听着  我们每天穿越星门
Look, we head through the gate every day
探索远方世界
Exploring distant worlds,
可是除了几个海洋生物学测试
And yet, with the exception of a few marine biology tests,
我们还没弄清
We have barely scratched the surface
自己所在的这个星球
Of the very planet that we occupy.
那是因为这儿风平浪静
That's 'cause there's nothing there.
我的意思是彻底调查一下无伤大雅
My point is it wouldn't hurt to be thorough.
我的意思是你在说废话
My point is your point is pointless.
浪费时间
And a giant waste of time.
该死的
Aah! dammit.
肖  欢迎你
Xiao, welcome.
亚特兰蒂斯欢迎你
Atlantis welcomes you.
十分荣幸能够
It is with great pride that i--
你好  理查德
Hello, richard.
肖
Xiao.
欢迎来到亚特兰蒂斯
Welcome to atlantis...
深感荣幸
With... great pride.
我很期待这次旅行
I'm looking forward to the grand tour.
这样
Well, then...
走么
Shall we?
好的
Yes.
这儿是控制室
This is the control room--
实际上  这里是整个城的中心
For all intents and purposes, the city's nerve center.
技术人员对他们的工作
These technicians are the very best
完成的堪称完美
At what they do.
跆拳道练的怎么样  阿米丽亚
How's the kickboxing going, amelia?
好极了  长官  多谢关心
Great, sir. thanks for asking.
你好啊  恰特
Hello there, chet.
是恰克
It's chuck.
什么
Excuse me?
是恰克  长官  我叫恰克
It's chuck, sir. my name is chuck.
是啊  恰克
Oh, of course. chuck.
恰特是夜班
Chet's on the late shift.
没人叫恰特
There is no chet.
我想改装一下
I think it would be a simple matter
城市的短程传感器应该不难
Of reconfiguring the city's short-range sensors
可以实现
In order to achieve--
我只看到你的嘴唇在动
You know, I can see your lips moving
但没在听你说
But I'm not hearing any sound.
不用一小时
It would take
不用一小时就可以
It would take less than an hour
准备好必要的调整
To make the necessary adjustments.
好吧  知道么
All right, you know what?
如果对你来说真的这么简单这么重要
If it is so simple and that important to you,
你为什么不自己去弄
Why don't you just go ahead do it yourself?
因为我需要得到你的允许
Because I require your authorization.
没问题
You got it.
谢谢  罗德尼
Thank you, rodney.
知道么  你很有可能
You realize it's highly unlikely
一无所获
You're actually going to find anything.
那我就得花一个小时
Then I would have wasted an hour of my time
听你说教"早告诉过你了"
And you'll be able to tell me "i told you so."
另一方面  如果我真的有所发现
If, on the other hand, I do find something,
他们说不定会给我个头衔
Perhaps they'll name something after me for a change.
指挥亚特兰蒂斯的探索工作
The prospect of commanding the atlantis expedition
令人畏惧
Was a daunting one.
韦尔博士和卡特中校
Dr. weir and colonel carter
他们的行为令人捉摸不透
Were incredibly tough acts to follow.
你表现的很好啊  理查德
Yet you availed yourself nicely, richard.
这九个月你都挺过来了
And you survived your nine months here.
我想不仅仅是挺过来吧
Well, I like to think I've accomplished a little more than mere survival,
而且我肯定
And I'm certain
如果你有机会看我的报告
That once you've had a chance to review my report--
没那个必要了
That won't be necessary.
就是说我通过考验了
So I'm receiving my graduation papers?
当然
Of course.
介于你在这儿出色的表现
In recognition of the great job you've done here,
勘察顾问组任命你为
The i.o.a. is appointing you
地球新环境部门的主席
As chair of earth's new environmental initiative.
恭喜你  理查德
Congratulations, richard.
你就要回来了
You're coming home.
好了  短程传感器好了
All right, short-range sensors are good to go.
可以开始扫描了
Start the sweep.
扫描开始
Sweep initiated.
很好
Great.
大概要三十分钟
So it should take about 30 minutes
来扫描整个星球
To scan the entire planet,
也就是说我有大把时间
Which means I've got plenty of time
去一下餐厅
To get down to the cafeteria,
吃点杏仁脆饼
Get myself some of that fine almond biscotti
太棒了
And a yoohoo,
然后准时回来
And be back in time
等你告诉我啥都没发现
For you to tell me you have found nothing.
我们有发现了
We've found something.
是啊  当然了
Yes, of course we did.
无论什么
Whatever it is,
它在海平面以下大概1500尺处
It's sitting approximately 1,500 feet below sea level.
你好  约翰
Hello, john.
克亚
Kolya?
我无法理解你的反应
I don't understand your reaction.
九个月前你是那么害怕到这儿来
Nine months ago, you were dreading coming over here.
九个月可以改变很多东西
A lot has changed in nine months.
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
而且  说实话
And, quite frankly,
我不喜欢半途而废
I don't like the idea of leaving a job unfinished.
我做得很好
I've done good work.
我的记录就是证明
My record speaks for itself.
究竟发生了什么
What's really going on?
勘察顾问组觉得
The i.o.a. is concerned
你做的一些决定
About some of the decisions you've made,
与协议冲突
Decisions that have run counter to protocol
说实话也不合常理
And, quite frankly, common sense.
他们...我们...
They... we...
觉得这个职位对你来说
Feel that the demands of this position
是屈才了
Have compromised your judgment,
是时候做些改变了
And it's time for a change.
这里
Right here.
行了
That'll do.
这东西究竟在下面多久了
I wonder how long it's been down there.
想想  如果我们没发现它
To think, it would have remained undiscovered
如果我们没
If we hadn't have...
短程传感器改装的不错
Nice job on reconfiguring the short-range sensors.
谢谢
Thank you.
推测得也不错
Nice job on the... wild guess.
谢谢
Thank you.
可以开始了么
Shall we?
可以
Yes.
再找找
Keep looking.
他们无处可逃
There's nowhere for them to go.
他们是科学家
They're scientists.
相信我
Trust me.
他们跑不快
They don't run very fast.
你醒了
Oh, you're awake.
留点力气吧
Save your energy.
这次你跑不掉了
You're not getting away this time.
我杀了你
I killed you.
你射中了我  这不一样
You shot me. there's a difference.
不  我杀了你
No. I killed you.
贝克特确认
Beckett confirmed it.
你已经死了
You were dead.
没错  他肯定这么认为
Yeah, I'm sure that's what he thought.
那就说说你的朋友吧
Let's just say your friend--
他叫什么来着  卢休斯
What was his name? lucius?
那天他不是唯一
He wasn't the only one
使用古人技术的
Using ancient technology that day.
你是怎么来这儿的
How did you get here?
你怎么找到我们的
How did you find us?
貌似你的那些外世联系
Turns out some of your off-world contacts
没你想的可信啊
Aren't as trustworthy as you think.
你的秘密泄露了  谢帕德
Your secret's out, sheppard.
朝那个方向走半天
A half day's walk in that direction
就能到达陆地的边缘
Will bring us to the edge of the mainland.
我觉得
I figure
坐船去亚特兰蒂斯可能要两天
It'll take us maybe two days to reach atlantis by boat.
你连城都进不去
You won't even get to the city.
他们会直接把你吹飞的
They're going to blow you out of the water.
不会的  他们根本看不到我们来
No. they won't even see us coming.
他们会忙着数死尸
They'll be too busy counting their dead.
你要干什么
What are you going to do?
通过星门送点炸药
Send an explosive through your gate,
瓦解城里的防御
Cripple the city's defenses.
为此
But for that,
我得问你要点东西
I'm going to need something from you.
我想你称之为虹膜解除码
I think you call it an idc.
去死吧
Go to hell.
没错
Yeah,
我就知道你需要劝劝
I thought you would need some convincing.
康拉德博士  瓦纳萨
Dr. conrad. vanessa.
进来吧
Come in.
希望没打搅到你
I hope I'm not intruding.
当然不会  什么风把你吹来的
Not at all. what brings you by?
也许这不太合适
This may be wholly inappropriate,
但是我想知道
But I was wondering
你想不想一起看电影
Whether you'd like to catch a movie.
电影
A movie?
今晚在放我最喜欢的两部
They're screening two of my favorites tonight--
《一路顺风》
Planes, trains, and automobiles
《偷心大少》
And  dirty rotten scoundrels.
说实话
Truth be told,
我今天很不爽
I'm having a horrible day
没心情笑了
And I'm not in much of a laughing mood.
那就等到明天吧
Then we can wait until tomorrow
明天要放《女为财死》和《袋鼠杰克》
When they'll be screening mad money and  kangaroo jack.
你想聊点什么吗
Is it something you'd like to talk about?
看来我们没空聊了
It seems the time for talk has passed.
我刚刚收到通知
I've just been informed
我不能在亚特兰蒂斯
That I'm being relieved of my command
继续指挥了
Here on atlantis.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为什么
Why?
显然  我在不够循规蹈矩
Apparently, I'm not very good at toeing the company line.
我以为我得到这个职位
I assumed I got this position
是因为我的记录良好
on the strength of my record.
但很明显
But now it's clear
他们指派我的原因
That the only reason they appointed me
是因为他们希望
Is because they expected
我会向他们妥协
I would just roll over for them.
那就别
Then don't.
什么
What?
别向他们妥协
Don't roll over for them.
反抗
Fight this.
我不能
I can't.
已经决定了
The decision's been made.
如果真是这样
If that was true,
那他们为什么不直接通知你
Then why didn't they just forward you a communique
而是派人花三周时间
Instead of sending a mouthpiece
赶到飞马座星系转告你呢
On a three-week journey to the pegasus galaxy?
你真的指望
Did you really expect me
我一点都不反抗就放弃么
To just give up without a fight?
老实说  是的
Honestly? yes.
我以为这件事你会用常识去处理
I assumed you'd let common sense Guide you on this one.
你不是来解雇我的
You weren't sent here to fire me.
你是来评估我的表现的
You were sent here to evaluate my performance
然后根据评估作推荐
And make a recommendation based on your findings.
勘察顾问组也许早有想法
The i.o.a. may be leaning a certain way,
但他们尚未对我的命运
But they have yet to make a decision
作出决定
On my fate.
但你  作为代表已经做出决定
Yet you, their representative, clearly have...
这让我觉得
Which leads me to assume
其中另有隐情
Something else is going on here.
勘察顾问组中的某个人
Someone in the i.o.a.
想赶我走
Wants me gone
他利用你赶我走
And is using you to make sure that happens.
告诉我吧  肖
Tell me, xiao.
你收了什么好处
What are you getting in return?
是我的职位  对吗
It's my job, isn't it?
他们许诺让你做亚特兰蒂斯的指挥官
They've promised you the atlantis command
只要你赶走了我
If you help them get rid of me?
这就简单多了
This will all go a lot easier
只要你接受事实
If you just accept where this is going--
我会才怪
The hell I will.
理查德  一切都在我掌控中
Richard, I hold all the cards.
我有决定权
The decision is in my hands.
这场仗你赢不了
This is a fight you cannot win.
你是我认识的最能忍的人
You can tolerate more than any man I've ever known.
为什么
Now, why is that?
我结过婚
Well, I was married once.
你在飞马座星系中
You're here in the pegasus galaxy
保卫你的人民
To protect your people,
但大部分时间你是徒劳
But half the time, you can't even do that.
这就是你的动力吧
That's what drives you, isn't it?
你曾经的失败
Your past failures.
你觉得不给我虹膜解除码
do you think By not giving me the idc
就能保住你的人民吗
You're keeping your people safe?
你只是在做无谓的反抗
You are just putting of the inevitable.
都完了
It's over
你保护不了他们
You can't protect them.
你和那些科学家
You, those scientists,
在亚特兰蒂斯的朋友
Your friends back at atlantis--
他们就要死了
They're as good as dead.
敬酒不吃吃罚酒
Well, I see that asking nice isn't working.
我得改变计划了
I'm going to have to make other plans.
我的位置  来两个人
Two men report to my position.
马上到
On our way.
几分钟之后
In a couple of minutes,
你就会求着给我虹膜解除码了
You're going to wish you'd given me that idc.
忙什么呢
What are you working on?
根据这个
According to this,
这个装置正以振动形式
The device is emitting a low-level energy signature
发射低能量的信号
In an oscillating pattern.
危险么
Is it dangerous?
不  辐射很小  但
No. radiation's minimal, but--
这不重要
Unimportant.
我们应该主要看数据
We should be focusing on the data.
我有啊
I was.
我已经尽我所能
Like, I've run every kind of decrypt sweep
进行了解码扫描
I can think of at this thing.
还是一无所获
Still nothing.
我思维枯竭了
I don't know what to do.
你会想到怎么办的
Oh, you'll think of something.
真的
Really?
为什么这么肯定
What makes you so sure?
因为你聪明绝顶
Oh, because you're brilliant.
这倒是真的  但也不是说...
That's true. Doesn't mean I'm going to--
等等  你刚刚说什么
Wait a minute. What did you say?
为什么这么说  你病了么
Why did you say that? What are you, sick?
还是我病了
Am I sick?
你听到什么了
What've you heard?
没人病了  罗德尼
No, nobody's sick, Rodney.
我说你聪明绝顶  因为你就是
I said you were brilliant because... because you are.
我很少说
I rarely say it
是因为你不好恭维
because you're a difficult man to compliment.
你骄傲  自负  顽固...
You're egotistical, you're arrogant, stubborn--
但还是聪明绝顶
And brilliant.
是的  罗德尼
Yes, Rodney.
聪明绝顶
And brilliant.
谢谢了
Thanks.
搬张椅子过来  瑞迪克
Well, pull up a chair, Radek.
我们有活儿干了
We've got some work to do.
好的...
All right...
告诉我B计划是什么
Tell me what plan B is,
还是你想给我一个惊喜
Or are you just going to surprise me?
我会派人你修理
I'm going to have my men repair the damage
你那艘被他们弄坏的飞船
they did to your puddle jumper,
顺便用来攻城
Then use it to attack the city.
我不想泼你冷水
Well, I hate to be Mr. Negative,
但你们至少
But I can think of
会遇到一个问题
at least one problem you're going to run into.
我知道  我很清楚开飞船
Yes, I know all about the ancient gene
需要古人基因
needed to operate the jumper.
但那不成问题
But that's not going to be a problem
你可以助我们一臂之力
because you're going to give us a hand.
抓住他
Hold him.
最后一次机会  小约翰
Last chance, Johnny boy.
给不给我虹膜解除码
You going to give me that idc?
看是不给了
Didn't think so.
你真有意思  谢帕德
You're an interesting man, Sheppard.
一路来到另一个星系
You travel to another galaxy,
不惜自己的生命来保护一群
Risk your life defending a bunch of people
你甚至不认识的人
you don't even know.
如果你问我
If you ask me,
你是视死如归呢
You're either someone with a death wish
还是要逃避什么
or someone running away from something.
告诉我
So tell me,
你在逃避什么
what are you running away from?
你去哪儿了
Where have you been?
到处都去了
All over.
这个装置发出的电磁辐射
The electromagnetic radiation this device is giving off
覆盖了整个城  甚至外围
Covers the entire city and well beyond.
你不是说不危险么
I thought you said it wasn't dangerous.
是不危险  至少根据这个...
Oh, it's not. At least, according to this--
它运作的频率很低
It's operating at a relatively low frequency.
我觉得  顶多
I think, at worst,
会引起一些人头疼
Some people may experience headaches
或失眠
Or trouble sleeping--
那就在睡觉前关了它
Well, then, we'll shut it off before bedtime.
同时
In the meantime,
你得看看这些数据
You should be focusing on the data.
我没看出什么
I'm not getting anywhere with that.
尽管说我是个天才
I mean, despite the fact that I am a genius.
我说你聪明绝顶  但没说你是个天才
I said you were brilliant. I didn't say you were a genius.
没差
Aw, same diff.
我不明白
I don't get it.
这些密码看上去比我们以往
You know, this script appears to be a lot less complicated
遇到要简单得多
than many we've encountered.
只有12个字符
It's only 12 symbols
不停地重复不同的组合
in an endlessly repeating yet varying sequences.
是啊
Yeah.
我同意
I agree.
很奇怪
It's very curious.
就好像要破解外星人的
It's like being asked to figure out the password
电脑密码一样
For an alien laptop or something.
我觉得如果我们...
I think that if we--
怎么了  你在干什么
What? What are you doing?
我在破解外星人的密码
I'm figuring out the alien's password.
罗德尼  我开玩笑的
Rodney, I was kidding.
不  有点道理...
No, it makes sense--
连小孩都用口令保护电脑
Every kid with a computer password-protects.
或许外星人也用
Why wouldn't an alien?
有了
There.
为什么我之前没注意到
Why didn't I see that before?
什么
What?
文字不是重点
The pattern isn't in the text.
关键是文本中的空白
It's in the spaces in between the text,
每个都是12个字符长
Each exactly 12 symbols in length.
每段文本长都是12的倍数
Each section of text is a multiple of 12--
24  48  96
24, 48, 96...
之间有12个字符长的空白
Separated by a 12-symbol space.
是个猜谜
Look, it's-- it's a puzzle.
这是个提示
It's a prompt.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
用模式识别软件
Running pattern recognition software
处理这12字符序列
on the 12-symbol sequence.
最好能找出一个12字符的组合
Hopefully I can come up with a 12-symbol permutation
能让我进入装置系统
that I can feed directly back into the device.
如果我是对的...
And if I'm right--
如果我们是对的...
If we're right--
就能进入外星人的电脑
We unlock the alien laptop.
你占了我的秘密领地
You poached my private spot.
什么
What?
我是说...
Uh... what I meant to say is
你发现了我的秘密基地
You discovered my little personal area.
我想独自思考问题时就来这儿
This is where I come to be alone with my thoughts.
不介意分享吧
Do you mind sharing it?
当然不
Not at all.
这里很美
It's beautiful.
真希望能永远呆在这儿
I wish I could stay here forever.
顺便说一句
By the way,
我想谢谢你  为今天的事
I wanted to thank you for earlier today.
我听了你的建议
I took your advice.
他们让步了
Are they backing down?
也不是
Unlikely.
但至少
But at the very least,
我可以大摇大摆的离开了
I have the satisfaction of knowing I went out swinging.
你是个好人  理查德
You're a good man, richard.
我真希望他们能看到这点
I really wish they could see that.
瓦纳萨  要不要和我一起吃晚饭
Vanessa, would you like to have dinner with me tonight?
这是我的荣幸
It would be my pleasure.
太好了
Wonderful.
那我什么时候来大摇大摆的来接你
What time should I swing by to pick you up?
我想偶遇会更好
It might be easier if we just met up.
伍尔希先生  你的传呼
Mr. Woolsey, you're off radio.
麦凯博士要求马上见你
Dr. Mckay needs to see you right away.
这记录了一个消失文明的
That is the historical, scientific,
历史  科学  科技
and technological records of an extinct civilization,
如果这个装置预示着什么
And if this device is any indication,
一定是很先进的
a highly advanced one at that.
比如  医学上的重大突破
I mean, medical breakthroughs,
先进武器的使用说明
Specifications for advanced weaponry--
这太不可思议了
This is incredible.
是啊
It... is.
我嗅到了"但是"
I sense a "but".
不不不
No, no, no. no, no, no.
没有"但是"
No "buts".
顶多有个"顺便说一句"
A "by the way", maybe.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
就像我说的  这个装置里记录了
Like I said, the device contains the records
一个消失很久的文明
For a long-dead civilization.
但也同时含有构成硅基生命形式的
But it also contains the chemical building blocks
化学基础物质
For a silicon-based lifeform.
什么意思
What does that mean?
这个装置是用来
This device was designed
在星球上播撒种子
to seed planets with organisms
而这些种子会进化成为一种有意识的种族
That would, in time, evolve into a sentient race.
当该种族发展到
Once that sentient race
一定的智能水平
Reached a certain level of intellectual maturity,
他们就可以受益于
They could then benefit
祖先留下的信息
From the information left for them by their extinct ancestors.
然后怎么样
So what happened?
不知道
I'm not sure.
很明显  他们还没有完成旅程
Obviously, they didn't complete their journey.
就被我们捞上来了
They ended up here instead.
在代达罗斯号的帮助下
Still, with the help of the daedalus,
我们可以肯定
We could ensure
他最终抵达了目的地
That it finally reached its target destination.
好吧  复制下数据就把它送回去
Okay, let's copy the data and then send it on its way.
马上就要"顺便提一句"了
Which is where the "oh, by the way" comes in.
这个装置的设置
Look, this device is set up in such a way
是一旦读取数据
that accessing the data
就会对生物样本造成不可挽回的伤害
would do irreparable damage to the biological samples.
也就是说  要么要么
In other words, it's either/or?
要么读取数据  要么把它送回去
Either we take the data or we send it on its way.
不可兼得
We can't do both.
你真让我失望  约翰
You disappoint me, John.
我觉得你不是这么容易被打倒的
I didn't think you'd be this easy to break.
即便是和你一起来的两个科学家
Even those two scientists you came with
在被杀之前
put up more of a fight--
都能负隅顽抗一下
Before we killed them.
又葬送了两条命
Just another two you couldn't save.
搞定了
We're done.
能运作么
It's operational?
能  我们用基因物质将其初始化
Yes, we used the genetic material to initiate it.
听到了么  谢帕德
You hear that, sheppard?
我们搞定飞船了
We've got the jumper--
长官  我们可以搞定亚特兰蒂斯后
Sir, we can come back and deal with him
再回来解决他
once we're done with Atlantis.
不行
No.
得先解决他
We deal with him now.
找出来  杀了他
Find him and kill him.
你好  艾伦
Hello, Ellen.
你好  路人甲
Hello... you.
阿米丽亚  能不能帮我个忙
Amelia, could you please do me a favor
给瓦纳萨·康拉德博士发个消息
and pass on a message to Dr. Vanessa Conrad?
她住在科学公寓里
She's in one of the science departments.
转告她
Please tell her that,
因为麦凯博士发现
Given Dr. Mckay's recent findings,
我们共进晚餐的事需要另行安排
We may have to reschedule our dinner tonight.
康拉德医生  长官  你确定吗
Dr. conrad? are you sure, sir?
倒不如
Better yet,
你告诉我她住在哪儿好了
Why don't you just tell me where her quarters are?
我亲自跟她说比较好
I suppose it's only proper that I tell her personally.
没有资料  长官
There's nothing here, sir.
还没给她安排住处么
She hasn't been assigned quarters yet?
根据记录  亚特兰蒂斯没有叫康拉德的博士
No sir, according to this,there is no Dr. conrad on atlantis
阿米丽亚  我说的是早些时候
Amelia, the woman I was talking to
你来找我时  和我说话那个女的
When you approached me earlier today...
长官
Sir?
在看台那儿
On the balcony.
在你转达麦凯博士的留言时
The woman I was speaking with
跟我说话的那个女人
When you delivered the message from dr. mckay.
或许我来之前  她就离开了
She probably left before I got there, sir.
当我到达看台时
When I approached you on the balcony,
你是独自一人
You were alone.
你很正常
There's nothing wrong with you.
究竟是怎么回事
What's going on?
待会儿告诉你
Uh, I'll let you know in a second.
我正在分析你的数据
I'm just looking over your results.
不会有什么结果
She won't find anything.
根据检查  你没事
According to this, you're fine.
健康得很
Perfectly normal.
看吧
See?
那是怎么回事
Then what is going on?
为什么数据库里没有你的名字
Why isn't your name in the database?
为什么之前阿米丽亚
Why couldn't amelia see you
看不见你
Earlier today?
我很确定数据库里有我的名字
Uh... I'm pretty sure my name is in the database.
至于阿米丽亚
And as for amelia,
如果她不是有什么病的话
If she has a medical concern,
不可能看不见我
There's no reason why she shouldn't see me.
她什么时候过来的
When did she come by?
理查德  她看不见我的
She can't see me, richard.
只有你看得见我
Only you can see me.
为什么
Why?
我得澄清下误会
I'd like to clarify the misunderstanding.
我不希望她认为我无视她
I don't want her thinking I turned her away.
阿米丽亚那边没事
Uh... amelia's fine.
我会跟她谈
I'll talk to her.
好
Great.
那么你说
Um, as for you,
你一直感觉不好
You said you've been feeling unwell?
是的
Uh... that's right.
疲劳么
Tired?
有点
Somewhat.
视觉上有什么症状么
Any visual symptoms?
看东西的时候
Shadows or flashes
有黑影或者光点么
In your field of vision?
可以这么说
Sort of. yes.
那听觉症状呢
What about auditory symptoms?
时常有响声  嗡嗡声  嘘嘘声
Occasional ringing or buzzing or whistling?
我们要谈谈
We need to talk.
是的  有时有嗡嗡声
Yes. the occasional buzzing.
私下谈谈
Somewhere private.
现在又来了
There it goes again.
我猜你是因为试用期审核的事
I bet you haven't been sleeping very well,
弄得睡眠不足
What with this whole probationary review...
有道理
Of course.
正是如此
That's it exactly.
很明显你压力很大
You're obviously under a lot of stress,
焦虑能通过各种方式
And sometimes anxiety can manifest itself
表现出来
In a variety of ways,
这些药物能让你放松
But these are going to help you relax
睡个安稳觉
And sleep through the night.
希望充足的休息后
And hopefully, once you're well rested,
你能感觉好点
You'll be feeling much better,
药到病除
And your symptoms will disappear.
如果还是如此
But if they don't,
再回来复诊
Come back and see me.
好吗
Okay?
谢谢了  医生
Thank you, doctor.
我建议你不要吃
I wouldn't advise taking those.
你站在那儿多久了
How long have you been standing there?
抱歉
Sorry.
我只是...不想打扰你
I just... didn't want to disturb you.
你好像在沉思
You seemed deep in thought.
我常常沉思
I'm always deep in thought.
让我反应敏捷
Keeps me sharp.
保持清醒
And sleepless.
那  你在干什么
So, what are you working on?
我在分析那些
I'm just analyzing the readings
装置显示的
From the radiation
放射读数
The device is emitting.
天啊  又是放射
Oh, jeez, again with the radiation.
我只是在伍尔希允许我们
Hey, I'm just killing time
查询资料之前
Till woolsey gives us the green light
打发打发时间
To start data retrieval on that thing.
你认为他会么
You think he will?
当然  这很重要
Of course. this is huge--
外星种族成就编年史
The chronicled achievements of an alien race,
开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
慢着
Whoa, wait a minute.
怎么了
What?
那装置发出的
The modulated, ultra-low frequency
超低频率射线
Emanating from the device...
我貌似在哪儿见过
I've seen something like this before.
不会吧
Oh, no.
抱歉搞得你莫名其妙
I'm sorry I made you doubt your sanity.
你是谁
Who are you?
你是什么
What are you?
我是你潜意识中对
I'm a physical manifestation
浪漫和异性渴望的虚拟呈现
Of your subconscious romantic and sexual ideals.
天啊
Oh, god.
你没疯
You're not crazy.
你真的能看到我
You're really seeing me.
为什么
Why?
我很抱歉对你说了谎
I'm sorry I had to deceive you,
但整个文明的生死存亡
But the survival of an entire civilization
命悬一线
Is at stake.
这是跟麦凯博士
This has something to do
修好的装置有关吧
With that device dr. mckay recovered,
对么
Doesn't it?
理查德
Richard?
她看不到我
She can't see me.
在
Yes
我还以为你在和别人聊天
I thought I heard you talking with someone.
没有
No.
我在准备一个演讲
I was running through the pep talk
我要给他们讲讲微生物学
I'm going to be giving the gang in microbiology.
真的么
Really?
你也知道
You know,
我今天看到你在看台上
I saw you on the balcony this afternoon
自言自语
Talking with... yourself.
有时...我喜欢把自己的想法说出来
I... occasionally do verbalize my thoughts.
让我更好地整理思路
It helps me put things in perspective.
细心的人就会发现这种行为
A casual observer might find that sort of behavior
令人不安
A little disconcerting,
特别是面对重大抉择时
Especially coming from someone in your position...
何况你又身居要职
Faced with a very important decision.
又记上一过了是么
Oh, another nail in my coffin?
麦凯博士向我简述了一下重修的装置情况
Dr. mckay briefed me on the device he recovered.
那是伟大的发现
Yes, it is an impressive find.
但不属于你
That doesn't belong to you.
拜托...请坐
Please-- sit down.
他告诉我你很迟才允许
He tells me you've delayed giving the go-ahead
他们修复数据库
On the data retrieval.
我不确定
I'm not sure
麦凯博士是否说明了我们目前的困境
If dr. mckay explained the dilemma we're facing--
我不敢相信你竟然
I can't even believe you're considering
听之任之
Letting this slip away.
还有别的问题需要考虑
There are other issues to consider--
例如
Such as?
另一个种族的命运
The fate of another race.
你能不能给我消停会儿
Will you stay out of this!
恕难从命
I will do no such thing.
他们的文明不复存在
Their civilization is dead.
相反  我们的文明正蓬勃发展
Ours, on the other hand, is very much alive,
这是很重要的情报
And we could use that information.
我们的虐夺使
We'd be robbing a civilization
他们的文明无法重建
Of the opportunity to rebuild itself.
文明是否能重新萌芽
There's no guarantee that a civilization will evolve
还尚未可知
From the seeding process.
或许在达到情感认知程度前
The entire race could die out
就已经灭绝
Before it even reached sentient status.
而我们就错失了
And we would be throwing away
千载难逢的机会
An incredible opportunity.
或者把潜在的数十亿生命
Or consigning billions of potential lives
扼杀在摇篮之中
To oblivion.
理查德  我不敢相信你如此好运
I can't believe your good fortune, richard.
这是你的机会
This is your opportunity
回到家乡向你的下属展示
To show the team back home
你的领导才能
That you can play ball.
按规章办事  才能保住饭碗
Follow procedure and save your job,
要么向我辞职  你自己选
Or you can hand it to me on a silver platter.
你竟然恐吓我
How dare you threaten me.
这不叫恐吓  理查德
It's not a threat, richard.
只是告诉你
I'm simply telling you
如果没了那个装置
How things are going to play out
事态将会如何发展
If we lose that device.
理查德  拜托
Richard, please.
他们是友好和平的种族
They were a kind and peaceful race,
应当得到救赎
One well worth saving.
我们得毁了它
We need to get rid of it!
那装置发出的能量指标
The energy signature that device is giving off
和我们在m1b-129碰见的
Is very similar to one we encountered
十分相似
On m1b-129.
它可以让人产生强大幻觉
It can induce mass hallucinations.
或者以一种通讯的方式
Or function as a means of communication
和不同种族的人交流
Between two very different species.
速战速决
Let's act quickly.
修补数据
Salvage the data
毁灭装置
And destroy the device.
多谢大家独到的见解
Thank you all-- both for enlightening me.
我会很快做出决定
I'll make my decision shortly.
请
Please.
现在
Now...
告诉我到底怎么回事
Why don't you tell me what's going on?
时间也够久的了
This has gone on long enough.
换手吧
Use your other hand.
继续
Go on.
我可不想让你就这么死了
I have no intention of letting you die.
爬上来吧  约翰
Now, climb back up, john.
这就对了
That's it.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on here?
千百年前
Tens of thousands of years ago,
一个文明预见了自己的末日
A civilization foresaw its end.
经历了数百年进化之后
After millions of years of evolution,
这个名为斯卡瑞的种族
The race known as the sekkari
濒临绝种
Faced extinction.
意识到自救无望
Knowing they couldn't save themselves,
他们便利用最后的日子
They spent their final days
寻找重新来过的方法
Creating the means to start over.
他们制造了很多贮种器
They built seed carriers,
各自按预定轨道
Each with a different target world
发往不同的
Programmed into its navigation system,
能够提供他们
Worlds that would provide them
充足化合物的目标世界
With the chemical compounds necessary
让他们有机会生存繁衍
To produce, sustain, and develop life.
每个贮种器里还专门设有资料库
Each seed carrier also held a repository
用来存放斯卡瑞人的史料
Containing the history of the sekkari people--
他们的坚韧不屈  丰功伟绩
Their struggles, their achievements,
还有他们犯过的
And the mistakes
导致最终毁灭的错误
That ultimately led to their own destruction.
贮种器装备完善后
The seed carriers were outfitted
还安装了子空间通讯器
With subspace communicators
用来在到达目的地时
Designed to alert the group
发回通知
Once a seeding was successful.
50多个贮种器发出去了
Over 50 were launched.
没有一个完成使命
None achieved their goal.
我的这架出了故障
This unit malfunctioned.
便让它停在了最近的星球
I guided it to the nearest planet--
也就是这里
This world,
希望这里的环境
In the hope that it would prove suitable
有利于我们的生命进程
To the life-forming process.
但不行
It wasn't.
好在设备着陆了
This device survived re-entry
基本无损
Relatively unscathed,
于是接下来的2000年里
Then spent the next 2,000 years
就在海底度过了
At the ocean's bottom,
直到最近
Until recently,
它的休眠系统被唤醒
When its dormant systems were awakened
探测器采集到了
By its sensors picking up trace readings
你们水下飞船的跟踪数据
From one of your submerged puddle jumpers.
几周前麦凯博士从水下停泊舱
The one dr. mckay flew up out of the underwater bay
开走的那艘
Several weeks ago.
我扫描了你们的城市  然后联接了你
I scanned your city, and then I linked with you.
那你是什么
What are you?
我是贮种器的人工智能产物
I'm the seed carrier's artificial intelligence.
我的使命就是研究你
My aim was to study you,
接近你
To get to know you,
还有  实际上  指引你
And, eventually, direct you
帮助我完成这艘贮种器的使命
To help complete this unit's assignment.
所以你就操纵我
By manipulating me.
不是的
No.
弄清
By finding out
你是怎样一个人
What kind of person you were
我们才敢托付于你
In the hope that we could place our trust in you.
你难道不能
Couldn't you have simply
一开始就跟我们坦白
Communicated your situation to us
你的境况么
From the beginning?
请你理解
Please understand--
我是斯卡瑞人最后的希望
I am the last hope for the sekkari people.
不能冒险行事
I couldn't risk it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
作为士兵  你是个威胁
As a soldier, you were a threat.
如果需要人用武力保全资料室
If anyone was to use force to secure the repository,
非你们莫属
It would have been you,
军人
The military man.
所以我使你产生了幻觉  迷惑你
So I connected with your mind to distract you.
迷惑我
Distract me?
让我以为飞船被毁了
Making me think the jumper had been sabotaged
算不上什么迷惑
Would've been enough of a distraction.
你迟早会发现破绽
You would have discovered the subterfuge.
而我又不能维持稳定幻象过久
I'm unable to maintain a static illusion over time.
我必须控制着你的思想
It was necessary to keep your mind occupied.
你就这么决定了
And that's what you chose?
是你决定的
What you chose.
我没有完全控制你的想象
I didn't have full control over your hallucination
或是帮你发出指令
Or the direction it took.
是你的思想在起主导作用
It was your mind driving the diversion.
我不过是顺着你的思路走
I merely played along.
你的意思是  我自己拷问了自己
Are you saying I tortured myself?
你每天都自我拷问  约翰
You torture yourself every day, john.
但这次
But in this case,
是你自己的大脑
It was your mind
呈现了你内心最深层的恐惧
Manifesting your darkest fears.
你一直在自欺欺人
You were the architect of your own self-deception.
现在你已经知道了真相
Now you know the truth
该做决定了
And have a decision to make.
中校  你去哪儿了
Colonel, where were you?
你知不知道我们在这坐了多久
Do you know how long we've been sitting here--
别嚎了  上船
Shut up. get in the jumper.
打扰了  沈女士
Sorry to disturb you, ms. shen,
你有地球来的
But you've just received a secure transmission
加密口信
From earth.
可以接通吗
Can I patch it through?
来吧
Go ahead.
卢瑟
Luthor.
情况怎么样
How are things?
我想  通知你最近的发展形势
Well, but I felt it only fair to inform you
才算公平
Of recent developments here.
虽然我很肯定你更能胜任
As much as I believe you'd be a worthy candidate
理查德·伍尔希的职位
To replace richard woolsey,
但恐怕委员会的其他成员
I'm afraid the rest of the council
持反对意见
Feels otherwise.
看来我们要换成詹姆斯·库立芝
It looks like we'll be going with james coolidge instead.
库立芝
Coolidge?!
别担心
Don't worry.
你促成交接的功劳  还是会有奖励的
You'll still be rewarded for facilitating the transition.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你来坐国际勘察顾问组
You'll be chairing the i.o.a.'s
新环境部门的第一把交椅
New environmental initiative.
好  我走了
Well, I'm off.
我估计不久就能与你会合
I suppose I'll be joining you shortly.
别做放假打算了
Don't make any holiday plans.
你不会被调走的
You're not going anywhere.
我看你前途无量
I gave you a glowing review.
既然你的未来全凭我一纸公文
And since your future rests entirely on my report,
我很高兴第一个祝贺你
I'd like to be the first to congratulate you
新上任的亚特兰蒂斯远征队
As the new permanent commander
永久指令官
Of the atlantis expedition.
我没懂
I don't understand.
和你一样  理查德  我不是谁的傀儡
Like you, richard, I'm nobody's puppet.
他们昨天应该在传达任命前
They should've thought of that
就意识到这点
Before delivering yesterday's update.
祝你好运
Good luck.
昨天的任命
Yesterday's update?
我听不懂她在说什么  长官
I don't know what she's talking about, sir.
我们最近都没有联络记录
We haven't had a scheduled dial-out in days.
可以让我单独呆一会儿么  阿米丽亚
Could I have a moment alone, amelia?
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
我猜有你的功劳吧
I assume that you're responsible for that?
算个临别礼物
Consider it a going-away present.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧
Alrighty.
给  完全修好了  整装待发
Here we are, all fixed up and ready to roll.
完成使命前
What happens to you
你们准备怎么办
When you reach your final destination?
使命
Destination?
你是在和a.i.说话  是么
Ah, you're talking to the a.i., aren't you? uh...
我先启动生命装置
I'll start the process
让斯卡瑞生命萌发
That will give life to the sekkari,
然后我就再度休眠
And then I'll go to sleep
直到下一次需要我的时候
Until a time when I'm needed again.
约翰
John,
我想
I realize
这种经历你一定不喜欢
It may have been an unpleasant experience--
是啊  还好吧  是有一点
Yeah, well, just a little bit.
怎么  你也能看见她
What-- you can see her too?
我想告诉你
And I want you to know
让你经历这些我感到很抱歉
I'm sorry for what you had to go through.
阿波罗号准备起程了
The  apollo is ready to beam.
这艘小飞船会带你去目标星球
The ship will take you to your target planet.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
我不是想抱怨
I don't mean to complain or anything,
我花了一天中最好的时间
It's just that I have spent the better part of a day
保证这东西能正常运转
Making sure this was in working order.
我是不是也应该
It would be kind of nice
看看你的庐山真面目
To just get a little face time with the--
看吧  麦凯博士
Here you are, dr. mckay--
斯卡瑞人的真实形态
The true form of the sekkari.
精致
Neat.
祝你好运
Good luck.
"精致"
"neat"?
什么  她突然就出来了
What? i-- she caught me off guard.
你指望我说什么
What did you want me to say?
你又会怎么说
What would you have said?
诡异吧
Oh, "weird."
伍尔希先生
Mr. woolsey.
要不要一起吃
Would you care to join us?
实际上
Well, actually,
我还有报告要整理
I have some reports to file...
谢谢邀请
Thank you.
乐意加入
I'd love to join you.
其实你根本不知道
So, you really had no idea
你看到的东西
That what you were seeing
不是真的
Wasn't real?
相信我
Trust me,
那个幻象太逼真了  博士
The manifestations were very convincing, doctor.
你绝对想象不到
You wouldn't have known.
恕我冒昧
Well, with all due respect,
我猜他们自知糊弄不了我
I think they knew they couldn't fool me,
所以嘛  才没找我
So they, you know, didn't bother.
注意力都放在你俩身上了
They just concentrated on you two.
我不明白的是
You know what I don't get,
那个a.i.早上现身
Is the a.i. thing revealed itself that morning,
你下午就发现了那个装置
You discover the device that afternoon.
时间掐得多准
I mean, that's perfect timing.
中校说的对  巧的离奇
The colonel's right. that was very coincidental.
我知道你想说什么
And I know what you're implying,
不过我脑子很清醒
But my mind was clear.
就是因为我聪明
That device was found
才发现了那个设备
Because of my brilliant thinking
还有  虽说不想承认
And, as much as I hate to admit it,
但泽兰卡帮了点小忙
A little help from zelenka.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
泽兰卡在外世
Zelenka's off-world.
没有
No, he's not.
他昨天就回来了
He came back yesterday.
多诺万中尉
Lieutenant donovan had a nasty reaction
食物中毒的那个
To something he ate,
他们提前回来了
They came back early.
不是么
Didn't they?
哦  狗娘
Aw, son of a--
我看不完全是巧合
Guess it wasn't that much of coincidence
管他呢
After all.